<?xml version="1.0"?>
<ZopeData>
  <record id="1" aka="AAAAAAAAAAE=">
    <pickle>
      <global name="File" module="OFS.Image"/>
    </pickle>
    <pickle>
      <dictionary>
        <item>
            <key> <string>_EtagSupport__etag</string> </key>
            <value> <string>ts41272977.51</string> </value>
        </item>
        <item>
            <key> <string>__name__</string> </key>
            <value> <string>getting-started.yml</string> </value>
        </item>
        <item>
            <key> <string>content_type</string> </key>
            <value> <string>application/octet-stream</string> </value>
        </item>
        <item>
            <key> <string>data</string> </key>
            <value> <string encoding="cdata"><![CDATA[

sections:\n
  - title: Download and set-up\n
    level: 3\n
    items:\n
      - type: sub-section\n
        data:\n
          title: Bower\n
          level: 4\n
          items:\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: \'The easiest way to get started with Chartist.js is by using <a href="http://bower.io/" target="_blank">bower</a>:\'\n
\n
            - type: code\n
              data:\n
                lang: bash\n
                code: bower install chartist --save\n
\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        The bower package contains the JavaScript library, CSS as well as the Sass (SCSS) files.\n
                        You can then integrate the desired dependencies in your project and start using them\n
                        immediately.\n
\n
      - type: sub-section\n
        data:\n
          title: One, two, three, CSS!\n
          level: 4\n
          items:\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        The quickest way to get things up and running is by using the Chartist.js CSS files.\n
                        The CSS is compiled from the Sass files with the default class names which are also\n
                        configured in the JavaScript library. You can then override the default styles or\n
                        modify the CSS file, however, for customization it\'s recommended to use the Sass\n
                        version of Chartist.js.\n
\n
            - type: code-snippet\n
              data:\n
                id: simple-start\n
                lang: html\n
\n
            - type: heading\n
              data:\n
                level: 5\n
                title: Use a CDN alternatively\n
\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        If you\'d like to get started even faster you can also use a CDN to load Chartist.js. The\n
                        awesome people at jsDelivr provide a fantastic job in hosting libraries from over 42 POP Locations\n
                        around the world! They always update Chartist.js to the latest version immediately and\n
                        they do all that for free! Check out the <a href="http://www.jsdelivr.com/" target="_blank">jsDeliver website</a>\n
                        for more information.\n
\n
            - type: code-snippet\n
              data:\n
                id: simple-start-cdn\n
                lang: html\n
                button: Show CDN Code\n
\n
      - type: sub-section\n
        data:\n
          title: The Sass way\n
          level: 4\n
          items:\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        If you like to customize your charts you can either remove the CSS fully and write your\n
                        own selectors using the Chartist.js Sass mixins or you just use the Chartist.js Sass\n
                        settings file to customize the look and feel of your charts.\n
\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        Styling inline SVG with CSS is a breeze and you should also consider writing your own\n
                        selectors for your charts and using the Sass mixins. You can read more about using the\n
                        Sass mixins in the <a href="#advanced">advanced</a> section.\n
\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        To customize the style of your charts using the Sass settings file you should copy the\n
                        settings file to your own Sass folder.\n
\n
            - type: code\n
              data:\n
                lang: bash\n
                code: cp bower_components/chartist/dist/scss/settings/_chartist-settings.scss styles\n
\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        Then just import your copy of the settings file before you import the chartist.scss\n
                        file and change the settings in your copy as desired.\n
\n
            - type: code-snippet\n
              data:\n
                id: custom-include\n
                lang: scss\n
\n
            - type: heading\n
              data:\n
                level: 5\n
                title: Default settings\n
\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        The settings file contains all relevant variables used in the mixins and while\n
                        generating the default classes. You can simply change the settings for styling your\n
                        own charts. If you want to override certain settings based on state or pseeudo\n
                        selectors, you can use the individual mixins to only override specific styles.\n
\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        Take a look at the settings to see how to customize the style of the defalt Chartist.js\n
                        class selectors.\n
\n
            - type: code-snippet\n
              data:\n
                id: default-sass-settings\n
                button: Show default settings\n
                path: src/styles/settings/_chartist-settings.scss\n
                lang: scss\n
\n
  - title: Create your first chart\n
    level: 3\n
    items:\n
      - type: text\n
        data:\n
          text: >\n
                  In this section you\'ll go through a simple example of how to use Chartist.js in your project.\n
                  You\'ll learn the default stages you go through when creating and customizing a basic line chart.\n
                  If you\'d like to see more in depth and advanced examples you should check out\n
                  the <a href="#advanced">advanced</a> section or the <a href="examples.html">examples page</a>.\n
\n
      - type: sub-section\n
        data:\n
          title: As simple as it can get\n
          level: 4\n
          items:\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        Chartist provides you a very simple API to get started, however, while trying to follow the\n
                         best practice of relying on standards and clear separation of concerns it sometimes needs a small mind\n
                         shift in order to understand how things are meant to work within Chartist. Instead of specifying\n
                         your colors, line width and other style related things in the JavaScript API, you\'ll need to use\n
                         CSS in order to control your appearance.\n
\n
            - type: sub-section\n
              data:\n
                title: Creating a chart using aspect ratios\n
                level: 5\n
                items:\n
                  - type: text\n
                    data:\n
                      text: >\n
                              Because of the nature of responsive design it\'s important to understand that blocks in design like images,\n
                              videos and similar content need to be able to scale and adapt to the media. In order for an element to scale, you\n
                              need to rely on a certain aspect ratios (like 4:3, 3:2, 16:9 etc.) rather than specifying a fixed width and height.\n
\n
                  - type: text\n
                    data:\n
                      text: >\n
                              To designers this Idea is absolutely not new, but to developers this might be at first. However, when a designer talks\n
                              to a developer about the images being 320x240 on this page and 300x200 on that element, he actually just\n
                              translated his idea of using 4:3 and 3:2 images into pixels.\n
\n
                  - type: text\n
                    data:\n
                      text: >\n
                              With Chartist you can specify those ratios directly on containers without the need to calculate any fixed dimensions.\n
                              In order to create a chart that is using the aspect ratio of a golden section you can just add the class .ct-golden-section\n
                              to your container where you initialize Chartist.\n
\n
                  - type: text\n
                    data:\n
                      text: >\n
                              Here is a list of all available container ratios (If using the Sass version of Chartist you can also easily add others):\n
\n
                  - type: table\n
                    data:\n
                      id: container-aspect-ratio-classes\n
                      button: Show available aspect ratios\n
                      header:\n
                        - Container class\n
                        - Ratio\n
                      rows:\n
                        -\n
                          - .ct-square\n
                          - \'1\'\n
                        -\n
                          - .ct-minor-second\n
                          - \'15:16\'\n
                        -\n
                          - .ct-major-second\n
                          - \'8:9\'\n
                        -\n
                          - .ct-minor-third\n
                          - \'5:6\'\n
                        -\n
                          - .ct-major-third\n
                          - \'4:5\'\n
                        -\n
                          - .ct-perfect-fourth\n
                          - \'3:4\'\n
                        -\n
                          - .ct-perfect-fifth\n
                          - \'2:3\'\n
                        -\n
                          - .ct-minor-sixth\n
                          - \'5:8\'\n
                        -\n
                          - .ct-golden-section\n
                          - \'1:1.618\'\n
                        -\n
                          - .ct-major-sixth\n
                          - \'3:5\'\n
                        -\n
                          - .ct-minor-seventh\n
                          - \'9:16\'\n
                        -\n
                          - .ct-major-seventh\n
                          - \'8:15\'\n
                        -\n
                          - .ct-octave\n
                          - \'1:2\'\n
                        -\n
                          - .ct-major-tenth\n
                          - \'2:5\'\n
                        -\n
                          - .ct-major-eleventh\n
                          - \'3:8\'\n
                        -\n
                          - .ct-major-twelfth\n
                          - \'1:3\'\n
                        -\n
                          - .ct-double-octave\n
                          - \'1:4\'\n
\n
                  - type: text\n
                    data:\n
                      text: >\n
                              Use the following HTML code to specify a container with one of the above aspect ratio classes.\n
\n
                  - type: code\n
                    data:\n
                      code: \'<div class="ct-chart ct-perfect-fourth"></div>\'\n
                      lang: html\n
\n
                  - type: text\n
                    data:\n
                      text: >\n
                              When using a fixed aspect ratio container you can then simply initialize your chart without\n
                              specifying any width or height in the options.\n
\n
                  - type: code-snippet\n
                    data:\n
                      id: simple-start-aspect-ratio-chart\n
                      lang: js\n
\n
            - type: sub-section\n
              data:\n
                title: Creating a chart with fixed dimensions\n
                level: 5\n
                items:\n
                  - type: text\n
                    data:\n
                      text: >\n
                              In order to create a simple line chart with fixed width and height you only need to have a\n
                              container element and initialize Chartist.js on it.\n
                              Give the container the class ct-chart so that it will get the default styles (if you don\'t\n
                              use your own classes).\n
\n
                  - type: code-snippet\n
                    data:\n
                      id: simple-start-fixed-chart\n
                      lang: js\n
\n
            - type: sub-section\n
              data:\n
                title: More than one chart on my page?\n
                level: 5\n
                items:\n
                  - type: text\n
                    data:\n
                      text: >\n
                              The example above uses the chartist default class to select the element where the chart should\n
                              be created. This class is important for applying the right styles in the CSS of Chartist. If\n
                              you need to create individual charts on one page, you should use IDs to initialize them separately.\n
\n
                  - type: code-snippet\n
                    data:\n
                      id: two-charts\n
                      lang: html\n
\n
      - type: sub-section\n
        data:\n
          title: The configuration of your chart\n
          level: 4\n
          items:\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        Chartist.js is built very flexible and almost everything within your charts can be configured.\n
                        In the default settings (that you can check in the <a href="api-documentation.html">API Documentation</a>)\n
                        you\'ll get some predefined defaults applied to your charts.\n
\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        You can always override the default settings of your charts by passing in a configuration\n
                        object at creation time.\n
\n
            - type: example-chart\n
              data:\n
                id: simple-configuration-chart\n
                classes: ct-golden-section\n
                show-code-button: Show code and comments\n
\n
      - type: sub-section\n
        data:\n
          title: Responsive sugar topping\n
          level: 4\n
          items:\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        Responsive web design is all based on\n
                        <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Guide/CSS/Media_queries" taget="_blank">media queries</a>\n
                        as you are probably already aware. Media queries are great and they help you to define media related\n
                        conditions that you can use to apply different styles for different media.\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        Sometimes it\'s also required to have different behavior on certain media and it\'s possible that\n
                        a specific component of your web site should behave in an other way on a small media than on a\n
                        large one. Luckily there is window.matchMedia in your browser that comes to the rescue. With\n
                        matchMedia it\'s possible to let your javascript react differently based on CSS3 media queries.\n
\n
            - type: heading\n
              data:\n
                level: 5\n
                title: Responsive setting overrides\n
\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        Configuring different chart behavior for various media is made simple with an override\n
                        mechanism. The priority of the override mechanism is based on order of specification of\n
                        the matching media queries.\n
\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        The following example uses different label interpolations (to save some space) on small media\n
                        as well as different spacing between the bars of the bar chart series. Resize your browser window\n
                        to see the effect.\n
\n
            - type: example-chart\n
              data:\n
                id: example-simple-bar\n
                classes: ct-golden-section\n
                type: Bar\n
                show-code-button: Show code and comments\n
\n
            - type: hint\n
              data:\n
                title: Cross-browser support\n
                classes: hint-cross-browser\n
                text: >\n
                        For IE9 you need to use a matchMedia polyfill. You should take a look at\n
                        <a href="https://github.com/paulirish/matchMedia.js/">Paul Irish\'s matchMedia polyfill</a>. Make\n
                        sure you include matchMedia.js as well as matchMedia.addListener.js as always both are needed\n
                        to polyfill the full specification of window.matchMedia.\n
\n
      - type: sub-section\n
        data:\n
          title: Different configuration for different series\n
          level: 4\n
          items:\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        Chartist also allows you to add specific configuration overrides for your series. This is useful\n
                        if you want to combine different looks for your series on the same chart.\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        You can even take this one step further by again overriding your series configuration in some\n
                        responsive settings overrides. This sounds complicated but it actually is very simple. Check the\n
                        example code with inline comments below to see how easy it is.\n
            - type: example-chart\n
              data:\n
                id: example-line-series-override\n
                classes: ct-golden-section\n
                show-code-button: Show code\n
\n
  - title: Styling your chart\n
    level: 3\n
    items:\n
      - type: text\n
        data:\n
          text: >\n
                  You should always use the power of CSS to make your data pop into your visitors eyes. I know\n
                  I’m telling this over and over but it’s all about a clean separation of concerns. In this chapter\n
                  you’ll find some useful information on how to style your charts with CSS.\n
      - type: sub-section\n
        data:\n
          title: Customizing the default CSS\n
          level: 4\n
          items:\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        Chartist comes with a highly customizable Sass file that allows you to customize all sorts of\n
                        appearance relevant things on your charts including colours used for series, line styles,\n
                        thickness and other properties. If you have the advantage of having a Sass build process at\n
                        your disposal, I highly recommend you to use the Sass version of Chartist instead of the\n
                        already prebuilt CSS. For more information on how to use the Sass version\n
                        please <a href="#the-sass-way">check out the Sass way of Chartist</a>.\n
\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        Chartist generates predefined classes for series by default. Those class names are alpha\n
                        numerated and always start with <code>ct-series-a</code>, where the letter a will be iterated\n
                        with each series count (a, b, c, d etc.). To address a specific series in styling, you’ll\n
                        need to create some styles for the corresponding series class name.\n
\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        Here is a list of selectors from the different chart types with some comments to explain what\n
                        properties can be used to influence the visual style of your charts.\n
\n
            - type: sub-section\n
              data:\n
                title: Line chart\n
                level: 5\n
                items:\n
                  - type: code-snippet\n
                    data:\n
                      id: custom-style-line-chart\n
                      lang: css\n
\n
            - type: sub-section\n
              data:\n
                title: Bar chart\n
                level: 5\n
                items:\n
                  - type: code-snippet\n
                    data:\n
                      id: custom-style-bar-chart\n
                      lang: css\n
\n
            - type: sub-section\n
              data:\n
                title: Pie chart\n
                level: 5\n
                items:\n
                  - type: code-snippet\n
                    data:\n
                      id: custom-style-pie-chart\n
                      lang: css\n
\n
            - type: sub-section\n
              data:\n
                title: Donut chart\n
                level: 5\n
                items:\n
                  - type: code-snippet\n
                    data:\n
                      id: custom-style-donut-chart\n
                      lang: css\n
\n
      - type: sub-section\n
        data:\n
          title: Colour up your charts\n
          level: 4\n
          items:\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        Colour is a core attribute of appearance and as you already know, we believe in strong\n
                        separation of concerns in web development. Therefore, Chartist does not include any options\n
                        within the JavaScript API to control colour of your charts.\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        This might first seem very inconvenient, but you’ll agree that it’s the right choice once you\n
                        need to change some colours in your web project where you’d need to go through some nasty\n
                        find-and-replace adventures in your JavaScript files to fix some colour mismatches.\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        The prebuilt CSS version of Chartist ships with 15 default colours that will be applied to your\n
                        chart series elements. If you just want to override some of these colours I recommend you use\n
                        the information\n
                        found in <a href="#customizing-the-default-css">how to customize the default CSS of Chartist</a>.\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        The following example illustrates how you’d override the colours of your line chart line and\n
                        point elements, within the two first sieries (ct-series-a and ct-series-b).\n
            - type: code-snippet\n
              data:\n
                id: colour-override-line-chart\n
                lang: css\n
\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        Note that on SVG elements there are two CSS properties for colourization. For strokes you\n
                        should use the <code>stroke</code> property and assign a CSS colour value. For fill areas you\n
                        can use the <code>fill</code> property. More information can be found in the above topics.\n
\n
            - type: sub-section\n
              data:\n
                title: Dynamic colouring\n
                level: 5\n
                items:\n
                  - type: text\n
                    data:\n
                      text: >\n
                              Often, predefined classes which can be used to colour your charts are fine but sometimes\n
                              CSS is not flexible enough to control all facets of dynamic appearance. While we could\n
                              build semantic classes like level1, level2, level3 and so on, we could then assign a\n
                              class dynamically, but still we’d need to rely on discrete values defined in CSS. One\n
                              lack of CSS today is that it does not incorporate dynamic values like mouse position\n
                              or placeholder variables that can be linked to JavaScript.\n
                  - type: text\n
                    data:\n
                      text: >\n
                              So, how do you go about your heat map chart or dynamically calculated line chart\n
                              strokes based on your data?\n
                  - type: text\n
                    data:\n
                      text: >\n
                              Chartist offers you a powerful tool for such kind of chart manipulations. The intrusive\n
                              event pipeline of Chartist allows you to hook into a <code>draw</code> event that allows\n
                              you to modify all your charts elements on the go while they’re drawn.\n
                  - type: text\n
                    data:\n
                      text: >\n
                              The following live code example shows you how to make a dynamically coloured chart\n
                              based on some data. Please go ahead and play around with the example, that’s what live\n
                              coding is for! For more information on how to use the <code>Chartist.Svg</code> API,\n
                              please <a href="http://gionkunz.github.io/chartist-js/api-documentation.html#module-chartistsvg">check\n
                              the API documentation</a>.\n
            - type: live-example\n
              data:\n
                title: Using draw events to modify chart elements\n
                level: 5\n
                id: example-dynamic-colours\n
                classes: ct-golden-section\n
                intro: >\n
                         By using the intrusive event pipeline of Chartist, you can easily change the behaviour of your\n
                         charts in a consistent and convenient way.\n
\n
  - title: Advanced\n
    level: 3\n
    items:\n
      - type: text\n
        data:\n
          text: >\n
                  In the following chapter you\'ll find some advanced usage examples that might be of interesst for you.\n
                  Chartist is very flexible because it relies on standard technology. This also means that you will need\n
                  to implement certain things yourself. This topic should cover some of these use-cases and give you some\n
                  basic idea why and how to implement certain functionality.\n
\n
      - type: sub-section\n
        data:\n
          title: Adding behaviour to your charts\n
          level: 4\n
          items:\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        This example shows you how you can easily build a tool tip on top of Chartist using jQuery and some\n
                        basic styling. It makes use of the ct-series-name and ct-value custom attributes that are present\n
                        on all SVG elements generated by Chartist.\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        We actually do a few things here that would go against a proper style guide (like animating with\n
                        JavaScript and changing styles instead of switching classes etc.), but this example is only for\n
                        illustrating how easy behavior could be attached to Chartist.\n
\n
            - type: example-chart\n
              data:\n
                id: behavior-with-jquery\n
                classes: ct-golden-section\n
                show-code-button: Show code\n
\n
      - type: sub-section\n
        data:\n
          title: Animations using Chartist.Svg\n
          level: 4\n
          items:\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        Usually we recommend using CSS for animations as it\'s closer to a clean separation of concerns.\n
                        However, sometimes you would want to animate SVG properties that are not available in CSS to animate.\n
                        For this purpose we have added a simple but powerful animation API that allows you to create SMIL\n
                        animations in a more convenient way.\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        In combination with the draw events of Chartist the animations are a very powerful and\n
                        flexible tool. You can intercept almost any step in chartist and if there is an SVG element\n
                        involved you can animate it using\n
                        <a href="api-documentation.html#chartistsvg-function-animate">Chartist.Svg.animate</a>.\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        The following simple example shows you how to created a delayed fade in effect for the a scatter chart.\n
                        You can also edit the example to play around with the settings.\n
\n
            - type: live-example\n
              data:\n
                title: Some SVG Animations can only be done with SMIL\n
                level: 5\n
                id: example-simple-svg-animation\n
                classes: ct-golden-section\n
                intro: >\n
                         Edit this example to figure out how to tweak animations. The force is strong in you young padawan!\n
\n
      - type: sub-section\n
        data:\n
          title: Switching axis type\n
          level: 4\n
          items:\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        The default configuration of the line chart is that it will use a step based X-Axis and an\n
                        automatic linear scale for the Y-Axis. This is all happening under the hood of Chartist and\n
                        already satisfies a lot of use-cases.\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        Sometimes though, it\'s not enough to have a fixed step chart and you\'d need something a bit\n
                        more complex. Something that allows you to plot those values along the X- and Y-Axis, instead\n
                        of just the Y-Axis. Sometimes, you\'d also want to specify the ticks on your chart manually\n
                        rather than having them auto calculated from Chartist.\n
            - type: text\n
              data:\n
                text: >\n
                        Of course Chartist wouldn\'t let you down with all those ideas you have in mind on how to\n
                        visualize your data!\n
\n
            - type: sub-section\n
              data:\n
                title: A line chart is only 1-dimensional?!\n
                level: 5\n
                items:\n
                  - type: text\n
                    data:\n
                      text: >\n
                              By default, Chartist uses <code>Chartist.StepAxis</code> for the X-Axis and <code>Chartist.AutoScaleAxis</code>\n
                              for the Y-Axis. Please read the <a href="api-documentation.html">API documentation</a>\n
                              if you\'d like to get more details, or available options on axis configuration.\n
                  - type: text\n
                    data:\n
                      text: >\n
                              The step based axis will not use any value for projection but rather rely on the index\n
                              of the given value to determine the position. This is fine for discrete steps of one\n
                              dimensional data, like we know it from regular Chartist charts:\n
                  - type: code-snippet\n
                    data:\n
                      id: 1-dimension-values\n
                      lang: js\n
                  - type: text\n
                    data:\n
                      text: >\n
                              What really happens with such one dimensional series data under the hood is that it will\n
                              be transformed into two dimensional data like so:\n
                  - type: code-snippet\n
                    data:\n
                      id: 2-dimensions-values\n
                      lang: js\n
                  - type: text\n
                    data:\n
                      text: >\n
                              You can see that Chartist will automatically convert one dimensional data into two\n
                              dimensional values where the previous value is assigned to <code>y</code> and <code>x</code> will be set to\n
                              <code>undefined</code>. As the default axis for projecting the <code>x</code> value\n
                              is a <code>Chartist.StepAxis</code> that relies on the value index rather than the\n
                              value, this is perfectly fine for the default setup.\n
\n
\n
            - type: sub-section\n
              data:\n
                title: Creating an XY-plot chart\n
                level: 5\n
                items:\n
                  - type: text\n
                    data:\n
                      text: >\n
                              In order to plot on the X-Axis too, we\'d need to switch the standard axis type\n
                              <code>Chartist.StepAxis</code> to something more continuous. Let\'s create a full fledged auto\n
                              scale chart that scales both the Y- and X-Axis automatically using\n
                              the <code>Chartist.AutoScaleAxis</code>!\n
                  - type: live-example\n
                    data:\n
                      title: Configure your axis type\n
                      level: 6\n
                      id: example-axis-auto\n
                      classes: ct-golden-section\n
                      intro: >\n
                               Note that we have just specified the X-Axis because the Y-Axis is configured to\n
                               <code>Chartist.AutoScaleAxis</code> by default.\n
                  - type: text\n
                    data:\n
                      text: >\n
                              A few things are different in this chart. Because\n
                              the <code>labels</code> array of our data is just used to be mapped as <code>ticks</code> option for the\n
                              default <code>Chartist.StepAxis</code> X-Axis, we can completely remove the labels from our data,\n
                              once we use a different axis than the step based one. Also you can see now from the\n
                              data series is that we are specifying 2-dimensional values directly.\n
\n
            - type: sub-section\n
              data:\n
                title: Fixed stuff can be sweet too!\n
                level: 5\n
                items:\n
                  - type: text\n
                    data:\n
                      text: >\n
                              The following example shows how to create an axis with some fixed ticks.\n
                              The <code>Chartist.FixedScaleAxis</code> can be used to create a more rudimentary\n
                              continuous linear scale, where ticks can be fixed either with an array of values or\n
                              with a divisor. For the detailed options please check\n
                              the <a href="api-documentation.html">API documentation</a>.\n
                  - type: live-example\n
                    data:\n
                      title: Unleash your creativity...\n
                      level: 6\n
                      id: example-axis-fixed-and-auto\n
                      classes: ct-golden-section\n
                      intro: >\n
                               Let\'s say we\'d like to fix a few ticks on the Y-Axis on our chart as those are the only\n
                               ones we\'re interested in. The X-Axis should be continuous too, but let\'s make\n
                               that axis a <code>Chartist.AutoScaleAxis</code>.\n


]]></string> </value>
        </item>
        <item>
            <key> <string>precondition</string> </key>
            <value> <string></string> </value>
        </item>
        <item>
            <key> <string>size</string> </key>
            <value> <int>35462</int> </value>
        </item>
        <item>
            <key> <string>title</string> </key>
            <value> <string>getting-started.yml</string> </value>
        </item>
      </dictionary>
    </pickle>
  </record>
</ZopeData>
