<?xml version="1.0"?>
<ZopeData>
  <record id="1" aka="AAAAAAAAAAE=">
    <pickle>
      <global name="File" module="OFS.Image"/>
    </pickle>
    <pickle>
      <dictionary>
        <item>
            <key> <string>_Cacheable__manager_id</string> </key>
            <value> <string>http_cache</string> </value>
        </item>
        <item>
            <key> <string>_EtagSupport__etag</string> </key>
            <value> <string>ts21897138.86</string> </value>
        </item>
        <item>
            <key> <string>__name__</string> </key>
            <value> <string>clojure.js</string> </value>
        </item>
        <item>
            <key> <string>content_type</string> </key>
            <value> <string>application/javascript</string> </value>
        </item>
        <item>
            <key> <string>data</string> </key>
            <value> <string encoding="cdata"><![CDATA[

// CodeMirror, copyright (c) by Marijn Haverbeke and others\n
// Distributed under an MIT license: http://codemirror.net/LICENSE\n
\n
/**\n
 * Author: Hans Engel\n
 * Branched from CodeMirror\'s Scheme mode (by Koh Zi Han, based on implementation by Koh Zi Chun)\n
 */\n
\n
(function(mod) {\n
  if (typeof exports == "object" && typeof module == "object") // CommonJS\n
    mod(require("../../lib/codemirror"));\n
  else if (typeof define == "function" && define.amd) // AMD\n
    define(["../../lib/codemirror"], mod);\n
  else // Plain browser env\n
    mod(CodeMirror);\n
})(function(CodeMirror) {\n
"use strict";\n
\n
CodeMirror.defineMode("clojure", function (options) {\n
    var BUILTIN = "builtin", COMMENT = "comment", STRING = "string", CHARACTER = "string-2",\n
        ATOM = "atom", NUMBER = "number", BRACKET = "bracket", KEYWORD = "keyword", VAR = "variable";\n
    var INDENT_WORD_SKIP = options.indentUnit || 2;\n
    var NORMAL_INDENT_UNIT = options.indentUnit || 2;\n
\n
    function makeKeywords(str) {\n
        var obj = {}, words = str.split(" ");\n
        for (var i = 0; i < words.length; ++i) obj[words[i]] = true;\n
        return obj;\n
    }\n
\n
    var atoms = makeKeywords("true false nil");\n
\n
    var keywords = makeKeywords(\n
      "defn defn- def def- defonce defmulti defmethod defmacro defstruct deftype defprotocol defrecord defproject deftest slice defalias defhinted defmacro- defn-memo defnk defnk defonce- defunbound defunbound- defvar defvar- let letfn do case cond condp for loop recur when when-not when-let when-first if if-let if-not . .. -> ->> doto and or dosync doseq dotimes dorun doall load import unimport ns in-ns refer try catch finally throw with-open with-local-vars binding gen-class gen-and-load-class gen-and-save-class handler-case handle");\n
\n
    var builtins = makeKeywords(\n
        "* *\' *1 *2 *3 *agent* *allow-unresolved-vars* *assert* *clojure-version* *command-line-args* *compile-files* *compile-path* *compiler-options* *data-readers* *e *err* *file* *flush-on-newline* *fn-loader* *in* *math-context* *ns* *out* *print-dup* *print-length* *print-level* *print-meta* *print-readably* *read-eval* *source-path* *unchecked-math* *use-context-classloader* *verbose-defrecords* *warn-on-reflection* + +\' - -\' -> ->> ->ArrayChunk ->Vec ->VecNode ->VecSeq -cache-protocol-fn -reset-methods .. / < <= = == > >= EMPTY-NODE accessor aclone add-classpath add-watch agent agent-error agent-errors aget alength alias all-ns alter alter-meta! alter-var-root amap ancestors and apply areduce array-map aset aset-boolean aset-byte aset-char aset-double aset-float aset-int aset-long aset-short assert assoc assoc! assoc-in associative? atom await await-for await1 bases bean bigdec bigint biginteger binding bit-and bit-and-not bit-clear bit-flip bit-not bit-or bit-set bit-shift-left bit-shift-right bit-test bit-xor boolean boolean-array booleans bound-fn bound-fn* bound? butlast byte byte-array bytes case cast char char-array char-escape-string char-name-string char? chars chunk chunk-append chunk-buffer chunk-cons chunk-first chunk-next chunk-rest chunked-seq? class class? clear-agent-errors clojure-version coll? comment commute comp comparator compare compare-and-set! compile complement concat cond condp conj conj! cons constantly construct-proxy contains? count counted? create-ns create-struct cycle dec dec\' decimal? declare default-data-readers definline definterface defmacro defmethod defmulti defn defn- defonce defprotocol defrecord defstruct deftype delay delay? deliver denominator deref derive descendants destructure disj disj! dissoc dissoc! distinct distinct? doall dorun doseq dosync dotimes doto double double-array doubles drop drop-last drop-while empty empty? ensure enumeration-seq error-handler error-mode eval even? every-pred every? ex-data ex-info extend extend-protocol extend-type extenders extends? false? ffirst file-seq filter filterv find find-keyword find-ns find-protocol-impl find-protocol-method find-var first flatten float float-array float? floats flush fn fn? fnext fnil for force format frequencies future future-call future-cancel future-cancelled? future-done? future? gen-class gen-interface gensym get get-in get-method get-proxy-class get-thread-bindings get-validator group-by hash hash-combine hash-map hash-set identical? identity if-let if-not ifn? import in-ns inc inc\' init-proxy instance? int int-array integer? interleave intern interpose into into-array ints io! isa? iterate iterator-seq juxt keep keep-indexed key keys keyword keyword? last lazy-cat lazy-seq let letfn line-seq list list* list? load load-file load-reader load-string loaded-libs locking long long-array longs loop macroexpand macroexpand-1 make-array make-hierarchy map map-indexed map? mapcat mapv max max-key memfn memoize merge merge-with meta method-sig methods min min-key mod munge name namespace namespace-munge neg? newline next nfirst nil? nnext not not-any? not-empty not-every? not= ns ns-aliases ns-imports ns-interns ns-map ns-name ns-publics ns-refers ns-resolve ns-unalias ns-unmap nth nthnext nthrest num number? numerator object-array odd? or parents partial partition partition-all partition-by pcalls peek persistent! pmap pop pop! pop-thread-bindings pos? pr pr-str prefer-method prefers primitives-classnames print print-ctor print-dup print-method print-simple print-str printf println println-str prn prn-str promise proxy proxy-call-with-super proxy-mappings proxy-name proxy-super push-thread-bindings pvalues quot rand rand-int rand-nth range ratio? rational? rationalize re-find re-groups re-matcher re-matches re-pattern re-seq read read-line read-string realized? reduce reduce-kv reductions ref ref-history-count ref-max-history ref-min-history ref-set refer refer-clojure reify release-pending-sends rem remove remove-all-methods remove-method remove-ns remove-watch repeat repeatedly replace replicate require reset! reset-meta! resolve rest restart-agent resultset-seq reverse reversible? rseq rsubseq satisfies? second select-keys send send-off seq seq? seque sequence sequential? set set-error-handler! set-error-mode! set-validator! set? short short-array shorts shuffle shutdown-agents slurp some some-fn sort sort-by sorted-map sorted-map-by sorted-set sorted-set-by sorted? special-symbol? spit split-at split-with str string? struct struct-map subs subseq subvec supers swap! symbol symbol? sync take take-last take-nth take-while test the-ns thread-bound? time to-array to-array-2d trampoline transient tree-seq true? type unchecked-add unchecked-add-int unchecked-byte unchecked-char unchecked-dec unchecked-dec-int unchecked-divide-int unchecked-double unchecked-float unchecked-inc unchecked-inc-int unchecked-int unchecked-long unchecked-multiply unchecked-multiply-int unchecked-negate unchecked-negate-int unchecked-remainder-int unchecked-short unchecked-subtract unchecked-subtract-int underive unquote unquote-splicing update-in update-proxy use val vals var-get var-set var? vary-meta vec vector vector-of vector? when when-first when-let when-not while with-bindings with-bindings* with-in-str with-loading-context with-local-vars with-meta with-open with-out-str with-precision with-redefs with-redefs-fn xml-seq zero? zipmap *default-data-reader-fn* as-> cond-> cond->> reduced reduced? send-via set-agent-send-executor! set-agent-send-off-executor! some-> some->>");\n
\n
    var indentKeys = makeKeywords(\n
        // Built-ins\n
        "ns fn def defn defmethod bound-fn if if-not case condp when while when-not when-first do future comment doto locking proxy with-open with-precision reify deftype defrecord defprotocol extend extend-protocol extend-type try catch " +\n
\n
        // Binding forms\n
        "let letfn binding loop for doseq dotimes when-let if-let " +\n
\n
        // Data structures\n
        "defstruct struct-map assoc " +\n
\n
        // clojure.test\n
        "testing deftest " +\n
\n
        // contrib\n
        "handler-case handle dotrace deftrace");\n
\n
    var tests = {\n
        digit: /\\d/,\n
        digit_or_colon: /[\\d:]/,\n
        hex: /[0-9a-f]/i,\n
        sign: /[+-]/,\n
        exponent: /e/i,\n
        keyword_char: /[^\\s\\(\\[\\;\\)\\]]/,\n
        symbol: /[\\w*+!\\-\\._?:<>\\/\\xa1-\\uffff]/\n
    };\n
\n
    function stateStack(indent, type, prev) { // represents a state stack object\n
        this.indent = indent;\n
        this.type = type;\n
        this.prev = prev;\n
    }\n
\n
    function pushStack(state, indent, type) {\n
        state.indentStack = new stateStack(indent, type, state.indentStack);\n
    }\n
\n
    function popStack(state) {\n
        state.indentStack = state.indentStack.prev;\n
    }\n
\n
    function isNumber(ch, stream){\n
        // hex\n
        if ( ch === \'0\' && stream.eat(/x/i) ) {\n
            stream.eatWhile(tests.hex);\n
            return true;\n
        }\n
\n
        // leading sign\n
        if ( ( ch == \'+\' || ch == \'-\' ) && ( tests.digit.test(stream.peek()) ) ) {\n
          stream.eat(tests.sign);\n
          ch = stream.next();\n
        }\n
\n
        if ( tests.digit.test(ch) ) {\n
            stream.eat(ch);\n
            stream.eatWhile(tests.digit);\n
\n
            if ( \'.\' == stream.peek() ) {\n
                stream.eat(\'.\');\n
                stream.eatWhile(tests.digit);\n
            }\n
\n
            if ( stream.eat(tests.exponent) ) {\n
                stream.eat(tests.sign);\n
                stream.eatWhile(tests.digit);\n
            }\n
\n
            return true;\n
        }\n
\n
        return false;\n
    }\n
\n
    // Eat character that starts after backslash \\\n
    function eatCharacter(stream) {\n
        var first = stream.next();\n
        // Read special literals: backspace, newline, space, return.\n
        // Just read all lowercase letters.\n
        if (first && first.match(/[a-z]/) && stream.match(/[a-z]+/, true)) {\n
            return;\n
        }\n
        // Read unicode character: \\u1000 \\uA0a1\n
        if (first === "u") {\n
            stream.match(/[0-9a-z]{4}/i, true);\n
        }\n
    }\n
\n
    return {\n
        startState: function () {\n
            return {\n
                indentStack: null,\n
                indentation: 0,\n
                mode: false\n
            };\n
        },\n
\n
        token: function (stream, state) {\n
            if (state.indentStack == null && stream.sol()) {\n
                // update indentation, but only if indentStack is empty\n
                state.indentation = stream.indentation();\n
            }\n
\n
            // skip spaces\n
            if (stream.eatSpace()) {\n
                return null;\n
            }\n
            var returnType = null;\n
\n
            switch(state.mode){\n
                case "string": // multi-line string parsing mode\n
                    var next, escaped = false;\n
                    while ((next = stream.next()) != null) {\n
                        if (next == "\\"" && !escaped) {\n
\n
                            state.mode = false;\n
                            break;\n
                        }\n
                        escaped = !escaped && next == "\\\\";\n
                    }\n
                    returnType = STRING; // continue on in string mode\n
                    break;\n
                default: // default parsing mode\n
                    var ch = stream.next();\n
\n
                    if (ch == "\\"") {\n
                        state.mode = "string";\n
                        returnType = STRING;\n
                    } else if (ch == "\\\\") {\n
                        eatCharacter(stream);\n
                        returnType = CHARACTER;\n
                    } else if (ch == "\'" && !( tests.digit_or_colon.test(stream.peek()) )) {\n
                        returnType = ATOM;\n
                    } else if (ch == ";") { // comment\n
                        stream.skipToEnd(); // rest of the line is a comment\n
                        returnType = COMMENT;\n
                    } else if (isNumber(ch,stream)){\n
                        returnType = NUMBER;\n
                    } else if (ch == "(" || ch == "[" || ch == "{" ) {\n
                        var keyWord = \'\', indentTemp = stream.column(), letter;\n
                        /**\n
                        Either\n
                        (indent-word ..\n
                        (non-indent-word ..\n
                        (;something else, bracket, etc.\n
                        */\n
\n
                        if (ch == "(") while ((letter = stream.eat(tests.keyword_char)) != null) {\n
                            keyWord += letter;\n
                        }\n
\n
                        if (keyWord.length > 0 && (indentKeys.propertyIsEnumerable(keyWord) ||\n
                                                   /^(?:def|with)/.test(keyWord))) { // indent-word\n
                            pushStack(state, indentTemp + INDENT_WORD_SKIP, ch);\n
                        } else { // non-indent word\n
                            // we continue eating the spaces\n
                            stream.eatSpace();\n
                            if (stream.eol() || stream.peek() == ";") {\n
                                // nothing significant after\n
                                // we restart indentation the user defined spaces after\n
                                pushStack(state, indentTemp + NORMAL_INDENT_UNIT, ch);\n
                            } else {\n
                                pushStack(state, indentTemp + stream.current().length, ch); // else we match\n
                            }\n
                        }\n
                        stream.backUp(stream.current().length - 1); // undo all the eating\n
\n
                        returnType = BRACKET;\n
                    } else if (ch == ")" || ch == "]" || ch == "}") {\n
                        returnType = BRACKET;\n
                        if (state.indentStack != null && state.indentStack.type == (ch == ")" ? "(" : (ch == "]" ? "[" :"{"))) {\n
                            popStack(state);\n
                        }\n
                    } else if ( ch == ":" ) {\n
                        stream.eatWhile(tests.symbol);\n
                        return ATOM;\n
                    } else {\n
                        stream.eatWhile(tests.symbol);\n
\n
                        if (keywords && keywords.propertyIsEnumerable(stream.current())) {\n
                            returnType = KEYWORD;\n
                        } else if (builtins && builtins.propertyIsEnumerable(stream.current())) {\n
                            returnType = BUILTIN;\n
                        } else if (atoms && atoms.propertyIsEnumerable(stream.current())) {\n
                            returnType = ATOM;\n
                        } else {\n
                          returnType = VAR;\n
                        }\n
                    }\n
            }\n
\n
            return returnType;\n
        },\n
\n
        indent: function (state) {\n
            if (state.indentStack == null) return state.indentation;\n
            return state.indentStack.indent;\n
        },\n
\n
        lineComment: ";;"\n
    };\n
});\n
\n
CodeMirror.defineMIME("text/x-clojure", "clojure");\n
\n
});\n


]]></string> </value>
        </item>
        <item>
            <key> <string>precondition</string> </key>
            <value> <string></string> </value>
        </item>
        <item>
            <key> <string>size</string> </key>
            <value> <int>14815</int> </value>
        </item>
        <item>
            <key> <string>title</string> </key>
            <value> <string></string> </value>
        </item>
      </dictionary>
    </pickle>
  </record>
</ZopeData>
