<?xml version="1.0"?>
<ZopeData>
  <record id="1" aka="AAAAAAAAAAE=">
    <pickle>
      <global name="File" module="OFS.Image"/>
    </pickle>
    <pickle>
      <dictionary>
        <item>
            <key> <string>_EtagSupport__etag</string> </key>
            <value> <string>ts41271270.02</string> </value>
        </item>
        <item>
            <key> <string>__name__</string> </key>
            <value> <string>CONTRIBUTING.md</string> </value>
        </item>
        <item>
            <key> <string>content_type</string> </key>
            <value> <string>application/octet-stream</string> </value>
        </item>
        <item>
            <key> <string>data</string> </key>
            <value> <string>Contributing to Chart.js\n
========================\n
\n
Contributions to Chart.js are welcome and encouraged, but please have a look through the guidelines in this document before raising an issue, or writing code for the project.\n
\n
\n
Using issues\n
------------\n
\n
The [issue tracker](https://github.com/nnnick/Chart.js/issues) is the preferred channel for reporting bugs, requesting new features and submitting pull requests.\n
\n
If you\'re suggesting a new chart type, please take a look at [writing new chart types](https://github.com/nnnick/Chart.js/blob/master/docs/06-Advanced.md#writing-new-chart-types) in the documentation, and some of the [community extensions](https://github.com/nnnick/Chart.js/blob/master/docs/06-Advanced.md#community-extensions) that have been created already.\n
\n
To keep the library lightweight for everyone, it\'s unlikely we\'ll add many more chart types to the core of Chart.js, but issues are a good medium to design and spec out how new chart types could work and look.\n
\n
Please do not use issues for support requests. For help using Chart.js, please take a look at the [`chartjs`](http://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/chartjs) tag on Stack Overflow.\n
\n
\n
Reporting bugs\n
--------------\n
\n
Well structured, detailed bug reports are hugely valuable for the project.\n
\n
Guidlines for reporting bugs:\n
\n
 - Check the issue search to see if it has already been reported\n
 - Isolate the problem to a simple test case\n
 - Provide a demonstration of the problem on [JS Bin](http://jsbin.com) or similar\n
\n
Please provide any additional details associated with the bug, if it\'s browser or screen density specific, or only happens with a certain configuration or data.\n
\n
\n
Pull requests\n
-------------\n
\n
Clear, concise pull requests are excellent at continuing the project\'s community driven growth. But please review [these guidelines](https://github.com/blog/1943-how-to-write-the-perfect-pull-request) and the guidelines below before starting work on the project.\n
\n
Guidlines:\n
\n
 - Please create an issue first:\n
   - For bugs, we can discuss the fixing approach\n
   - For enhancements, we can discuss if it is within the project scope and avoid duplicate effort\n
 - Please make changes to the files in [`/src`](https://github.com/nnnick/Chart.js/tree/master/src), not `Chart.js` or `Chart.min.js` in the repo root directory, this avoids merge conflicts\n
 - Tabs for indentation, not spaces please\n
 - If adding new functionality, please also update the relevant `.md` file in [`/docs`](https://github.com/nnnick/Chart.js/tree/master/docs)\n
 - Please make your commits in logical sections with clear commit messages\n
\n
Joining the Project\n
-------------\n
 - Active committers and contributors are invited to introduce yourself and request commit access to this project.  Please send an email to hello@nickdownie.com or file an issue. \n
\n
License\n
-------\n
\n
By contributing your code, you agree to license your contribution under the [MIT license](https://github.com/nnnick/Chart.js/blob/master/LICENSE.md).\n
</string> </value>
        </item>
        <item>
            <key> <string>precondition</string> </key>
            <value> <string></string> </value>
        </item>
        <item>
            <key> <string>size</string> </key>
            <value> <int>2991</int> </value>
        </item>
        <item>
            <key> <string>title</string> </key>
            <value> <string>CONTRIBUTING.md</string> </value>
        </item>
      </dictionary>
    </pickle>
  </record>
</ZopeData>
